字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
木浅
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
showeryhe
翻译
桃小兔吃冰棒
冬麟
翻译
静妹粒
时间轴
chance-coco  兜兜兜爹  抑郁郁
电脑狂人
第三季
第十集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
M网络
电池
椅子
Chairs.
有人在吗
Hello?
我来早了吗  我以为说的是九点
Am I early? I thought we said 9:00.
没有  是九点
Uh, no, yeah. Yeah, 9:00.
她到了吗
She here yet?
我知道她的飞机已经着陆了
Uh, I know her plane landed,
所以  只要她上了飞机就会来
so... as long as she's on it.
路上还好吧
The drive okay?
还好  因为是周末
Yeah, yeah. It's the weekend,
又碰上节假日  所以...
plus the holiday, so...
-对啊  -是啊  路上都没车
- Oh, right. - Yeah, there was no traffic.
-M网络是什么
- What's M-NET?
穆特尼最后的挣扎  改名
Mutiny's last-ditch rebranding effort.
想先止血  但是  你知道  还是...
Tried to stop the bleeding, but, you know, still--
流血了
Bled.
不管怎样  我的风投公司还留着这里的租赁权
Anyway, my VC firm held onto the lease
就是以防我们哪天需要个空场地
just in case we needed a raw space
给哪个小投资项目
for some tadpole investment.
真挺空的
It's pretty raw.
是啊  我们四年前搬进去时
Yeah, well, the building was in shambles
这里就像座废墟
when we moved in four years ago.
去年的地震肯定也帮了倒忙
I'm sure last year's quake didn't help.
天啊  那太糟了
Oh, God, that was crazy.
什么
What?
-地震  -是啊
- The earthquake. - Oh, yeah.
-那时你在哪  -工作
- Where were you? - Work.
-你呢  -也是
- How about you? - Work.
你是怎么想着来这儿开会的
How come you wanted to meet here?
不是我想的
Oh, I didn't.
是卡梅隆的主意  谁知道呢  也许
Cameron did. Who knows? Maybe...
她想再来看看
she wanted to see it again.
顺便说下  我...
By the way, I--
我不是有意没问你就邀请戈登来的
I didn't mean to invite Gordon without talking to you.
-没关系  没事  -但是我...
- No, no, it's fine. - But I--
我看了论文  觉得这件事很了不起
I just read the paper and I thought it was something phenomenal,
况且他还在运营我们建造的区域网络
and he's still running the regional network we built,
所以就没多想
so it was a no-brainer.
合情合理
Makes perfect sense.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry about that.
不用  真的  没事  我很高兴他能来
No, really, it's fine. I'm glad he's coming.
不  我是指  你们离婚了
No, I-- the divorce.
是啊
Right.
你们两个竟然...
That the two of you...
-是啊  -离婚了
- Yeah. - ...got a divorce.
不管怎样...
Anyway...
-真多谢你  -没事的
- I really appreciate it. - It's no problem.
我们就花几天看看
I mean, it's just a couple of days for us to see
是不是值得投入精力
if there's even a "There" There.
当然
Yeah, of course.
但是  我很激动
But... I'm excited.
我也很激动
I'm excited, too.
我真的挺兴奋的  我...
I'm really excited. I--
抱歉我来晚了
Hey, sorry I'm late.
卡梅伦来了吗
Is Cameron here?
多久没见了
How long has it been?
上次是什么时候  四月吗
What was that, April?
是啊  其实是两年前的四月
Yeah, it was actually two Aprils ago.
-天哪  这么久了吗  -嗯
- Oh, jeez, it's been that long? - Yeah. Yeah.
-你看上去不错  -你也是
- Well, you look good. - So do you.
不  说真的  你看上去不错
No, I mean it, you look-- you look good.
谢谢
Thank you.
我能
Hey, can I, uh...
能让我们单独聊会儿吗
Can you give us a sec?
当然了
Oh, of course. Absolutely.
你们想聊多久...
Take all the time you...
-我能...  -好
- Um, can I...? - Yeah.
怎么了
What's up?
我来你没问题吧
Hey, uh, you're okay that I'm here, right?
考虑到我在干的事情
I just thought it was an interesting concept,
我觉得这是个很有趣的理念
given everything that I've been working on.
还有我很多年没见过卡梅伦了
And, you know, I haven't seen Cameron in years.
但我不想...这是你的主意  行吗
But look, I don't-- this is your thing, okay?
我不想妨碍你  我不想干涉
I don't want to get in the way. I don't want to interfere.
戈登  没事的  我很高兴你能来
Gordon, it's fine. I'm glad you're here.
他  我不太确定
Him? I'm not so sure.
我不知道
Yeah, I don't know.
我们不再联系的部分原因就是...
Part of the reason we've been losing touch is...
你该看看我们上次见面时他的样子
Well, you should have seen him the last time I did.
乔
Hey, Joe.
很高兴你来了
Glad you're here.
好  我们先花点时间
Okay, let's just hold off for a second
聊聊万维网是什么
on trying to talk about what the World Wide Web is
我们集中讨论它能做什么
and let's focus on what it could do.
好了  背景是这样的
Okay, so, here's some context.
我们假设这些是大巨头
Let's say these are the big boys,
我们所熟知的围墙花园
the walled gardens we're all familiar with.
比如天才  计算机服务
You've got your Prodigy, CompuServe,
美国在线服务
your America Online--
America Online.
这是哪门子的名字
What kind of name is that, anyways?
听上去就像是尼尔·戴蒙德的歌
It sounds like a Neil Diamond song.
*我们来到了美国...在线*
*We're coming to America... Online!*
好了  还有国家科学基金网
Okay, and then we've got NSFNET.
伯纳斯·李在这篇论文中提出来的
Now, what Berners-Lee is proposing in this paper
是一个可以在网络的网络上
is an application that could
运行的应用
run on this network of networks.
国家科学基金网虽还不能用于商业用途
And now, well, NSFNET isn't for commercial use yet,
它一点也不性感
and it isn't, you know, sexy at all--
得了  国家科学基金网性感得流油
Hey, hey, come on. NSFNET's dripping with sex.
它的容量和范围令人敬畏
The size and scope of that would be formidable.
但它还是与围墙花园彻底隔绝
Still, it's completely separate from the walled gardens,
钱都在围墙花园那儿
where all the real money is.
现在  将这些网络联接起来
Right now, unifying all these networks
是根本不可能的
is essentially impossible.
他们的软件不同  协议不同
There's different software, different protocols,
基于不同硬件的不同操作系统
different operating system on different hardware.
但如果一个万维网这样的东西扩大
But if something like the World Wide Web expands,
最终就能做到
what it ultimately could do...
这样  没错吧
is this, right?
不对  不是的
Well, no, not really.
不是
No.
抱歉  我清楚你们没有邀请我
Sorry, I know I wasn't exactly invited.
可以吗
May I?
谢了
Thanks.
那好
Okay, uh...
如果我的理解无误
if I'm understanding this correctly,
会出现一种工具  能有办法
an implementation would somehow
让这些大规模在线网络
take these massive online networks
变成这样
and do this.
不  不对  你理解反了
No, no, you've got it backwards.
能把那个给我吗
Can you give me the thing?
好的
Good.
是这样  对吧
It's this, isn't it?
记住  万维网和国家科学基金网
Remember, the World Wide Web and NSFNET,
或者说因特网  随便你怎么叫吧
or the Internet, or whatever you want to call it,
是不同的两个东西
are two different things.
万维网是运行在因特网之上
The Web runs on top of the Internet.
它将一切都统一起来
It unifies everything.
将网络世界一体化
It makes it one network.
这才是其背后的惊人潜力
And that's the incredible potential behind something like this.
人类联合起来想兴建通天堂的巴别塔
为阻止该计划  上帝让人类语言不通而不能交流
罗赛达石是用三种语言刻了同一段诏书的石碑
目前的线上世界语言不通
Right now the online world is the Tower of Babel.
而这就是翻译机制
This is the Rosetta Stone.
在最先进的NeXT软硬件上运行
And it's running on state-of-the-art NeXT hardware and software.
那就是我最大的问题
That's my biggest problem.
NeXTSTEP不是问题  它很完美
NeXTSTEP is not a problem; it's perfect.
好吧  但我是做网络的
Okay, yeah, but I run a network
不是简单在白板上比划
that's not just on a whiteboard.
又来了
All right, here we go.
NeXT是最先进的系统
The NeXT is a state-of-the-art system.
其设计者乔布斯是个身败名裂的自大狂
Designed by a disgraced megalomaniac
他把外形看得比功能还重
who loves form over function.
难怪你喜欢NeXT
No wonder you love the NeXT.
听着  如果要说一个
Look, if we're talking about a network
只适用于一种与科技界其他产品
that lives exclusively on a ridiculously overpriced machine
都无法兼容的
that doesn't really play nice
天价机型的网络
with anything else in the technological landscape,
那么这其实是
what we're really looking at...
好吧  请
Well, please...
-是这样的  -尽管用
- Is this. - ...be my guest.
一座小小的荒岛
A tiny little desert island
根本没人在乎
that nobody gives a shit about.
卡梅伦  你怎么看
Cameron? What do you think?
好吧
Okay.
假如我们语言互通
Say we're all talking the same way.
好  我们说什么
Cool. What are we saying?
只是闲聊吗  玩游戏吗
Are we just shooting the breeze? Are we playing games?
找人打炮吗
Are we looking to get laid?
就漫无目的地购物吗
Are we just mindlessly shopping?
这点提的好
That's an excellent point.
内容很重要  但这盒子就相当于
Content is paramount, but this box is the equivalent
一个先进的五十万座体育场
of a 500,000-seat state-of-the-art stadium,
我们造出来  掌握在手里  就是胜利
and we build that, we own that, we win.
但是没有一个吸引人的乐队表演
But what's the point of having a giant stadium
要这么大的舞台又能干什么呢
if you don't have a kickass band to play the venue?
各位  现在我们最不需要的
Guys, the last thing that we need to do right now
就是着急上车
is hop in the car
冲去一个空荡荡的体育馆停车场
and race out to the parking lot of an empty stadium
听还没有发明的歌曲表演
before rock and roll is even invented.
各位  我们超前了
Hey, guys, we are early.
而且不只是"冲去国际薄烤饼店
And I'm not talking, "Let's all just run down to the IHOP
点一个银元薄煎饼"那么早
and grab some silver dollar pancakes" early.
我们的创意超前了太多年
We are years and years early on this.
相信我  好吗  我就是干这个的
Trust me, okay? This is what I do.
-你怎么能看不到  -我同意
- I can't believe you don't see this. - Look, I agree.
我同意互联网
Okay, the World Wide Web
也许是继切片面包之后最伟大的发明
could be the next best thing since sliced bread.
但现在  它还是一个运行在NeXT电脑上的
But right now, it's a tiny little academic petri dish
-学术研究实验  -在欧洲
- running on a NeXT computer. - In Europe.
-是的  在欧洲  -那我们还在干吗
- Yes, is Europe. - Then what exactly are we all doing here?
行了  等等
Okay, hold on, hold on.
别忘了已经达成的一致
Just-- let's not lose the shared idea here.
这是个共享协议  全球通用语言
There's a shared protocol. This is a universal language.
-世界语还全球通呢  -世界语又是啥
- So it's Esperanto. - What the heck is Esperanto?
是给学习不好的孩子的简单语言
It's a language for idiots that failed.
这样吧  我们休息一下吃个午饭吧
Okay, you know what? Let's-- why don't we take a break for lunch?
现在才10点30
It's, like, 10:30.
我可以吃点  好啊
I mean, I could eat. Sure.
戈登出去买披萨了
Gordon went out to get some pizza.
我想着你在日本肯定好久没吃到了
I figured maybe it'd been a while since you had that in Japan.
我们公寓转角就有家多米诺
There's a Domino's around the corner from our apartment.
你都大老远的来了
Look, you came all this way.
但是感觉你并不想待在这里
It just seems like you don't want to be here.
我不是说我会听听看吗
I said I'd listen.
唐娜  这又不是
Donna, it's not like this
我要在美国办的唯一一件事
is the only thing we're doing stateside.
我和雅达利还有约  汤姆还要见美国世嘉
I have a meeting with Atari. Tom has to meet with SEGA U.S.--
你还要和他家人在德州过圣诞  我知道
And you're doing Christmas in Texas with his family, I know.
卡梅  我们的安排就是照你的行程定的
Cam, we planned this whole thing around your travel.
在维加斯你还说这是个好主意
In Vegas you said this was a good idea.
是个好主意
It is a good idea.
但现实对它也有诸多限制
But is also has severe limitations in reality.
很高兴见到你  乔
It's good to see you, Joe.
谢谢
Thanks.
看到你过得很好我很高兴
It's good to see you doing so well.
-那你以为会是什么样  -不  只是
- As opposed to...? - No, it's just--
卡梅伦说  她说在分销商展览上
Cameron said-- she said at COMDEX you were--
你当时状态不太好  就这样
you were having a bit of a rough go of it, that's all.
那件事我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear about what happened.
我没见过莱恩  但卡梅伦对他评价很高
I never met Ryan, but Cameron spoke really highly of him.
挺难熬的
It was difficult.
很长一段时间都是
For a long time.
但自从跟你妻子恢复了联系
But I'm doing so much better
我好了很多
since I've reconnected with your wife.
慢着
Hold on-- -
我觉得我们在绕圈子
I feel like we're talking in circles.
我们真正想要的是...
What we're really looking at is...
我想从另一个角度入手
You know, I'd like to take things in a different direction,
如果可以的话
if I could.
我想谈谈我在巴黎学到了什么
I'd like to talk about what I learned in Paris.
巴黎
Paris?
异想天开的哑剧表演吗
The whimsical art of mime?
几周前我去了超文本大会
I went to the Hypertext Conference a few weeks ago.
-什么会  -超文本
- The what conference? - Hypertext.
一些非常著名的公司也去了  苹果  施乐
Some pretty big names were there-- Apple, Xerox.
-你没听说我有点意外  -我也很意外
- I'm surprised you didn't hear about it. - Yeah, me, too.
就是我们在计算机分销商展见面之后的事
It was right after I saw you in COMDEX.
好  知道了  超文本大会
Okay, so, Hypertext Conference.
伯纳斯·李也去了
Berners-Lee was there
他和所有愿意听的人交谈
and he was talking to anyone who would listen.
他分享了全部的网页开发工具包  传输协议
He handed out the entire Web toolkit, the transfer protocol,
标记语言  服务器软件
the mark-up language, the server software,
所有的一切
everything.
-慢着  你见到他了  -那些你都拿到了
- Wait, you met him? - You have all of that?
-是啊  -怎么今天早上不说
- Yeah. - That would have been useful to know this morning, maybe.
超文本
What's so interesting
这样的编程语言的有趣之处就在于
about a programming language like Hypertext--
它根本就不是编程语言
It's not a programming language,
它只是文本  可以访问其他文本
it's just a text that accesses other texts.
其实我指的是HTML  超文本标记语言
Yes, I'm actually talking about HTML, the mark-up language.
它的有趣之处在于它简单
What's so interesting about it is its simplicity.
只凭一套非常基本的规则
With a very basic set of rules,
就能创建很多页信息  对象
you can create pages of information, objects,
等带宽提高  还能创建媒体
and eventually media when the bandwidth increases.
所以我追着CERN的人谈了谈
So, I cornered the guys at CERN.
不好意思  CERN是什么
Sorry, what is CERN?
CERN  欧洲核子研究委员会
CERN. European Organization for Nuclear Research.
好吧  核研究  我明白其中的关联了
Oh, right, nuclear research. Okay, I see the connection.
抱歉  我没听见"C"代表什么
Sorry, I'm not hearing the "C" Word in it.
没人理会他们
Nobody was paying any attention to them.
他们让我有点想起
In a way, they reminded me of
1981年计算机分销商展览上的戈登和唐娜
Gordon and Donna, COMDEX '81.
-可怜吗  -是不是帅爆了
- What, pathetic?  - Devastatingly handsome?
超前于时代的天才
Geniuses ahead of their time.
伯纳斯·李分发的手册中不光有HTML
Berners-Lee handed out guidebooks not only for HTML,
还有HTTP  超文本传输协议
but HTTP, the transfer protocol,
在潜在网络上
the call-and-response process for
传输信息的呼应过程
moving information like this across to potential networks.
寻址协议就是TCP/IP
Addressing protocol is TCP/IP.
但HTTP是抽象应用层协议
But HTTP is the abstraction application layer protocol
以协同方式在TCP/IP之上
that sits on top of TCP/IP symbiotically,
对吧  汤姆
right, Tom?
有了HTTP  任何一台机器都能做客户端
With HTTP, any machine can become a client,
每台电脑都可以当服务器  轻松交换文件
any machine can become a server, easily exchanging files.
不  文件传输是FTP
No, files are FTP,
也就是文件传输协议
as in File Transfer Protocol.
名字里本来就有"文件"俩字
It's the one that has "file" in the name of it.
我是说HTTP会最终取代FTP
What I am saying is HTTP will eventually supplant FTP.
我的意思是它是全能的
What I'm saying is it can do it all.
这个说法有趣
That's interesting.
不是吧  FTP还有趣
Really? FTP? That's interesting?
我想再次强调非常重要的一点
I'd like to get back to an important point--
简洁性
simplicity.
HTML和HTTP都极致简洁
Both HTML and HTTP are breathtakingly simple.
而这种简洁让它用途广泛
And this kind of elegance allows for versatility,
具有通用性
it allows for universality--
没错  就像我说的  一种通用语言
Yes, a universal language, like I said.
而最妙的一点就是在线目录查看器
And the best part is, the online catalogue viewer,
传输协议和网页伺服器软件
the transfer protocol, the Web server software,
全部都是免费的
all of it is free.
我不赞成开源
I have a problem with open source.
-你不赞成  -没错
- You do? - Yeah, I do.
你知道我手上每天要过多少份
Do you know how many bad video game pitches
糟糕的电子游戏方案吗
I sit through every single day?
世嘉和任天堂长期保持水准的原因
The only way SEGA stays SEGA, or Nintendo stays Nintendo,
就是不让这些破烂游戏上市
is by not turning those pitches into products.
-这不是...  -不  不
- That's not-- - No, no.
因为开放源码
Because open source
就相当于让病人自己管理疯人院
allows the lunatics to run the asylum.
而每次  每一次
And every time-- every time--
你向世界推出精心编写的代码
you put well-made code out into the world,
放任阿猫阿狗拿来折腾
for people to screw around with,
就会产生极大的问题
it causes major problems.
你看看麦克米伦实用网络的事就知道了
I mean, just look what happened to MacMillan Utility.
-你说什么呢  -怎么了
- What are you doing? - What?
麦克米伦实用网络怎么了
What happened to MacMillan Utility?
天啊  源代码被发布到网上
Gee. The release of their source code online
股东的千万投资一夜蒸发
vaporized millions of shareholder dollars.
-长话短说  就是你出局了  -好了
- And, long story short, you're not around anymore. - Okay!
或者你也可以换个角度来看
Or you could look at it a different way.
如果大家能一起来创造万维网这样的东西
That with everyone creating something like the Web together,
也许会催生出非常了不起的结果
some potentially amazing things could happen.
首先  建设速度非常快
One, it gets built very fast.
其次  规模上也非常巨大
Two, it becomes huge in size.
第三  会不停地被人编辑优化
Three, it's constantly being edited and refined,
所以其升级速度也非常快
so it's improving at a massive rate.
第四  也不会有什么控制一切的霸主
And four, there's no overlord controlling things.
那你说的这个
And what network
浩瀚璀璨的协作网要在什么网络上运行呢
is this giant, miraculous nebula of collaboration happening on?
你和我都清楚这样的事
You know as well as I do that something like this
会极大改变因特网的面貌
could change the face of the Internet.
因特网现在还不能开放商用
The Internet is not available for commercial use.
你知道我投了多少钱给游说公司
Do you know how much money I poured into lobbying,
想尽快撤掉网络管制吗
trying to get deregulation through?
大家都盼着这事  而早晚也会撤掉
Look, everybody wants this and it's gonna happen eventually.
但我们赶得太早  而时机至关重要
But we are early, and it's all about timing.
如果时机不对  我们就完了
If the timing's off, we're dead.
穆特尼就败在了时机不对上
Timing's what killed Mutiny.
-时机才不是穆特尼失败的原因  -抱歉
- Timing didn't kill Mutiny. - I'm sorry...
英雄也可以造时势
The right people make it the right time.
我们完全可以推动这个
We can move this forward.
我们完全可以当那群创造未来的人
We can be the people that make that future happen.
-天啊  -怎么了
- Oh, my God. - What?
我听这套未来的说辞都听恶心了
I'm so sick of hearing about the future.
那到底是什么玩意  所谓未来
What is that? The future
无非就是一个糟心版的现在
is just another crappy version of the present.
人们编了这套好听的话
It's some bribe people offer you
哄着你违逆自己的心意  去干他们想做的事
to make you do what they want instead of what you want.
这一次  未来会有不同
This future can be different.
我的天  你该把这句话写在名片上  乔
Oh, Jesus, that should be on your business card, Joe.
你们还要上这句话多少次的当
How many times are you people gonna fall for this?
我同意乔
You know, I'm with Joe.
虽然我不相信我会这么说  但我支持乔
I can't believe I'm saying that, but I'm with Joe.
你当然支持乔  你们俩都是投钱的
Of course you're with Joe. You guys are the money people.
而我和卡梅伦才是实打实动手干的人
But it's me and Cameron that actually have to do it.
-可是现在什么都还没做  -没错
- Look, nobody's doing anything yet-- - Exactly.
几位  今天聊得很愉快
Yeah, uh, guys, it's been fun,
但我们得赶路去了
but I think we're gonna hit the road.
是啊  今天说得  很深入
Yeah, it's been, uh, thorough.
也行  那今天就这样  我们明早再碰头
Yeah, okay, we can call it a day and reconvene in the morning.
没准
Well, you know, maybe--
没准明天会好些
maybe tomorrow will go better.
明天他们不会来了
There's not gonna be a tomorrow.
卡梅伦
Hey, Cameron?
明天再来吧
Come back tomorrow.
你们从地球那边飞过来
You flew halfway across the world.
唐娜也在尽力  给她一个机会吧
Donna's trying. Just give her a chance.
乔
Joe...
我们得看看到底能不能成
We got to see if there's something here.
这就是一团乱  乔
This is a mess, Joe.
就是一团乱
It's just a mess.
拜托
Come on, now.
申请登船
Permission to come aboard?
允许登船
Permission granted.
-皮鞋要当心  -抱歉
- Careful there with them city shoes. - Oh, sorry.
你最好先适应适应  别晕船了
Might wanna wait a sec till you get your sea legs under you.
没事的
That's all right.
船不错
Cool boat.
不过车道上开不起来吧
Hard to sail in a driveway, though.
我上个月驾着船
Well, I was beating that slot
想穿过天使岛和金门大桥之间的海沟
up between Angel Island and Golden Gate last month,
在浅水区转弯不够快
and I didn't heel fast enough in the shallows
结果刮了好大一块漆皮下去
and I scratched the shit out of my gelcoat.
瞧瞧你
Well, look at you!
成老水手了
The salty sailor.
也瞧瞧你
Look at you.
嗯  我知道  真成大人了  对吧
Yeah, I know. Just all grown up, right?
其实  卡梅伦
Well, hell, Cameron,
在我认识你之前你已经是大人了
you were all grown up before I ever met you.
-啤酒  -好
- Beer? - Yeah.
今早上跟唐娜如何
How'd it go this morning with Donna?
你怎么
How did you...?
黛安跟我说了
Oh, Diane told me.
你以为这是谁家的车道
Whose driveway you think you're in?
黛安如何
How is Diane?
她还好  还好
She's good. Good.
-你们还...  -是啊
- Yeah? You guys are still-- - Yup.
她还在上班  我仍是退休赋闲
She still goes to work and I stay retired.
我们有的周末启航去索萨利托或蒂布龙
Some weekends we sail up to Sausalito or Tiburon.
如果时间充裕  通常会去葡萄园
Mostly go to the vineyard if we got a couple of extra days.
真是加州范儿
So Californian.
你带她去过德州吗
You take her to Texas yet?
去过
I have, yeah.
她喜欢牛仔比赛  其他都讨厌
Loved the rodeo. Hated everything else.
我觉得她说喜欢牛仔比赛也只是客气
And I think she was just being polite about the rodeo.
那下一步呢  办婚礼吗
So, what's next? Wedding bells?
我们当然商量过  但还是算了
Oh, sure, we've talked about it, but, no.
见鬼  我们加起来有三个孩子
Hell, between us we got three kids
介于14至35岁  够了
aged 35 to 14, and that's enough.
老汤米·兰顿怎么样
Hey, how's old Tommy Rendon?
准备要孩子了吗
Kids on the radar for you yet?
没
Ooh, no.
不  我
No, I--
汤姆想要  但
Tom wants them, but...
算了  如果要我决定
No. If it was up to me,
不如从自动贩卖机买
we'd just get them out of a vending machine
日本买东西都这样
like everything else in Japan.
-比如  -可食用内衣
- Like what? - Uh... edible underwear.
-不会吧  -是啊
- Come on! - Yeah.
再说  我们现在离家太远了
Plus, you know, we're just so far from home these days.
不过究竟什么才算是家呢
Although, what the hell is home anymore?
你现在在这儿  不是吗
Well, you're here now, ain't ya?
对  我在这儿
Yeah, I'm here.
我只用了24小时
It only took me 24 hours
就意识到不该回来
to realize that coming back was a mistake.
唐娜说那个点子很棒
Well, Donna says it's a pretty hot idea.
让你们都重聚一堂了  肯定很棒
Had to be to get all you yokels in the same room again.
确实  只是
It is. It's just...
人多误事
too many cooks.
耍我两次  是我笨了
Fool me twice, right?
是这样吗
Was that what happened?
你被耍了
You got fooled?
再说我还有
And also I just have
自己的事要忙  所以
my own thing going on that I'm busy with, so...
对  《太空摩托》
Yeah. Space Bike.
对
Yeah.
没错  我买了  我玩过了
That's right, I got it. I tried it out.
-是吗  -好吧
- Really? - Well, look--
不适合我
Well, it's not for me.
你安装了就够让我惊讶了
I am just amazed that you even installed it.
说实话  我真是搞不懂
I couldn't make heads or tails of it, to tell you the truth.
那个拿电锯的小混蛋是谁
Well, who's that little bastard with the chainsaw?
那是谁啊
Who's that one?
还有那个力场
And then you got the force field thing.
感觉根本赢不了啊
Hell, it's like you can't even win.
不能
Nope.
你赢不了
No, you can't.
抱歉  我来拿海莉的牙套
Sorry, I'm just here for Haley's retainer.
她又恰巧忘了
She conveniently forgot it again.
我在楼上看到了
Yeah, I think I saw it upstairs.
你是要我...我可以上...
Oh, did you want me to-- 'cause I can go--
不是  我去拿吧  进
No, no, I can get it. Come on in.
我
You know, I, uh...
每晚都还睡楼上
still sleep up there every night.
你要不自己倒杯葡萄酒
Hey, why don't you get yourself a glass of wine?
你看着需要喝一杯
You look like you could use one.
你知道在哪儿的
You know where it is.
浓汤制作的关键在于帕玛森干酪面包
The key to the bisque is the Parmesan toast.
四年前你还只知道帕玛森干酪粉
Four years ago, the only Parmesan you knew about was powdered.
嗯  我还有呢
Yeah, well, I still got that, too.
琼妮用勺舀着吃
Joanie eats it by the spoonful.
告诉你个小秘密
Dirty little secret?
十几岁女孩子跟同龄男孩一样惹人厌
Teenage girls are just as disgusting as teenage boys.
你有看到
Well, have you seen this thing
她拿巧克力糖浆干的事了吗
that she does with the chocolate syrup?
还有牛奶  真过分
And the milk? It's atrocious.
我的天
Oh, my God.
对  说到奶酪
Yeah, speaking of cheese,
乔·麦克米伦似乎又回到最佳状态了
seems like Joe MacMillan is back in rare form.
是啊  你去唤醒了那只野兽
Yes, you've gone and woken up the beast.
只有那样才能打动卡梅伦
Well, it was my only way to get to Cameron.
本就希望渺茫  而且也没奏效
It was a long shot and it didn't even work.
我只能自己去
I had to go myself.
我说不准  或许那样也没用
I don't know, maybe that didn't even work either.
你这些年还能怎么办
Yeah, well, what were you gonna do all these years, you know?
应付工作  照顾小孩
Between work and the kids?
难道能搭飞机去东京吗
You know, get on a plane and fly to Tokyo?
我可以向汤姆推销糟糕的电子游戏
Well, I could pitch a terrible video game to Tom.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
你根本没机会见到汤姆那么重要的人
You would never get a meeting with someone as important as Tom.
-如果明天他们真回来  -嗯
- You know, if they do come back tomorrow... - Yeah?
我准备了一个很棒的点子
I got this really great idea for them.
-说说看  -电子游戏点子
- Yeah, what's that? - For a video game.
就是一条传送带
Basically, it's this conveyor belt
上面全是电灯泡[点子]
filled with all these light bulbs,
要赶在它们点亮之前在上边拉屎[吐槽]
but you have to shit on them before they turn on.
我有个完美的标题
Wait, I have the perfect title.
听听看
Ready?
"你是个屁眼"[混蛋]
"You're an Asshole."
听我说
Listen, I--
很抱歉今天我说你是投钱的
I apologize today for calling you a money person.
我不是那个意思
I didn't mean it.
就是冲口而出
It just kind of came out.
但没说错
It's true, though.
现如今...
These days.
说不好  或许就是个错误
I don't know, maybe it was a mistake--
把大家聚在一起  想要修复一切
bringing everybody back together and trying to fix things.
如果明天没人来  我还是感兴趣的
Yeah, well, if nobody shows up tomorrow, I'm still interested.
真的  你今天不像是感兴趣
Really? It didn't seem like that today.
什么...我只是说  你太早了
What the-- all I said was, you're early.
我不说对大家没好处
Okay, it's a disservice to everyone if I didn't say that.
而且
You know, and look, I've--
我也错过
I've been wrong before.
我会第一个承认的
I'll be the first to admit that.
能问你个奇怪的问题吗
Can I ask you a weird question?
说吧
Yeah, shoot.
你现如今经常做爱吗
Are you having just a ton of sex these days?
我还行吧
I do all right.
你呢
How about you?
嗯  也是
Yeah. Same.
你
Are you--
现在有跟谁约会吗
are you seeing anyone right now?
没有
Nope.
很好
Good.
因为我有个奇怪的问题
'Cause there's something really weird I want to ask you.
你愿意...
Would you be open to...
见见谁吗
meeting someone?
约会那种
Like, for a date?
我觉得有个人跟你会很合得来
I think you and this guy would really hit it off.
什么
What?
是啊  我认识个很不错的人
Yeah, there's this really great guy I know.
他在加大负责一个电脑实验室项目
He runs the computer lab programs at Cal.
他非常好  我觉得
He's really nice and I just thought,
你也单身  他也是
you're free, he's free...
我也不知道
I don't know.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
我想完成讲演稿
I'm trying to finish this presentation.
但我电池耗尽了  所以我用你的
My battery died, so I'm using yours.
没事吧
Is that okay?
没事
Yeah, it's fine.
博斯怎么样了
How's Bos?
挺好的
Yeah, he's good.
听着
Oh, look...
我知道你今天不怎么开心
I know today wasn't fun for you,
明天如果你不想  就不用再去了
so if you don't want to come back tomorrow, you don't have to.
你还要去
So, you're going?
嗯
Well...
是啊
Yeah, I guess so.
那我也去
Okay, well, I guess I'm going, too.
好啊
Good.
我去洗澡
Let me get in the shower.
他是怎么了
What's up with him?
他说他需要五分钟
He says he needs five minutes.
我今早起来头好疼
Man, did I wake up with a headache this morning.
你昨晚离开得好快
Hey, you left kind of fast last night.
希望我没说什么蠢话
I hope I didn't say anything dumb.
约会的事
You know, about the date.
戈登  没事的
Gordon, it's fine.
好啊  那就好
Oh, great. I mean, you know, good.
把他的号码给我吧
I'd love his number.
除非...你会觉得别扭
Unless, you know-- if it would be weird...
不
No.
不会
No, I mean...
没问题
Yeah, no problem.
你来了
Oh, you're here.
你们都来了
You're all here.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
伯纳斯·李编写HTML是为浏览  编辑万维网
Berners-Lee wrote HTML to view and edit the Web,
编写HTTP是为了网络内部沟通
HTTP so that it could talk to itself.
通信网络可能嘈杂混乱
The chatter could be cacophonous.
也可能寂静无声
It could be deafeningly silent.
看大局  万维网会成为什么
Big picture-- what will the World Wide Web become?
简单回答  谁知道呢
Short answer-- who knows?
你想说什么
Okay, so, what's your point?
去设想万维网会成为什么样子
It's a waste of time to try to figure out
根本是浪费时间  我们不可能知道
what the Web will become. We just don't know.
因为现在  说到底
Because right now, at the end of the day,
它还是线上的学术研究目录
it's just an online research catalogue
只在NeXT上运行
running on NeXT computers
还局限于欧洲的小范围网络
on a small network in Europe.
那么你是说  我们来之后
So, you're saying everything we've talked about
说的一切都是浪费时间
since we got here has been a waste of time?
我是说  我们后退一步
I'm saying, let's take a step back.
真正的退后一步
Literally, a step back.
你在板子上写的是什么
Yeah, but what is this on the board?
是浏览器的代码
It's the code for the Web browser.
你给写在白板上了
And you wrote it all on the whiteboard.
线上学术研究目录
The online catalogue of research?
全是挪威人  物理论文
Full of Norwegian dudes, physics papers,
和粒子图表什么的吗
and particle diagrams and stuff?
我们为什么在意这个
Yeah, and we care about this because why?
我们怎么走到今天的
How did we all get here today?
我们做的决定
The choices we made,
我们的意志吗
the sheer force of our will, something like that?
还有一个答案  命运的吹动
Here's another answer-- the winds of fate.
随机巧合  无形之手推着我们前进
Random coincidence, some unseen hand just pushing us along.
宿命
Destiny.
我们今天怎么走进来的
How did we all get here today?
我们走过这扇门
We walked through this door.
我们不用建个大白盒子或体育场
We don't have to build a big white box or a stadium,
或是发明摇滚乐
or invent rock and roll.
我们一旦对万维网有特定的定义  就输了
The moment we decide what the Web is, we've lost.
我们如果想教别人拿它怎么办
The moment we try to tell people what to do with it,
就输了
we've lost.
我们只需要
All we have to do
建一扇门
is build a door
让他们进来
and let them inside.
我五岁时
When I was five,
我母亲带我去城里
my mother took me to the city.
我们穿过荷兰隧道  它很简单
And we went through the Holland Tunnel, and it was basic.
钢筋混凝土
Concrete and steel.
但我坐在后座  兴奋无比
But it was also my excitement sitting in the backseat,
不知什么时候轮到我们走出隧道
wondering when it was going to be our turn to emerge.
阳光像爆炸一样
It was the explosion of sunlight.
我们出了隧道时
And when we exited the tunnel,
曼哈顿全部展现在我们眼前
all of Manhattan was laid out before us.
那就是旅行最棒的部分
And that was the best part of the trip--
在一个了不起  没有尽头的东西里
the amazing possibility to be able to go anywhere
有无尽探索的可能
within something that is magnificent and never-ending.
这是第一个浏览器
This is the first Web browser,
CERN为审阅编辑研究建造的基本版本
the rudimentary one CERN built to view and edit research.
我写出来就是为了让你们看它多简单
I wrote it up here for you to see how simple it is.
只需要一块白板  这就是基本的钢筋混凝土
It takes up one whiteboard-- that's basic concrete and steel.
但我们可以拿它建造一扇门
But we can take this and we can build a door,
我们可以成为最早做的人
and we can be the first ones to do it.
因为现在  其他人都把它
Because right now, everyone else sees this as--
视为在线研究目录
As an online research catalogue.
在NeXT上运行
Running on NeXT.
在欧洲的一个网络上
On a network in Europe.
有了这些代码  我们就能建荷兰隧道
And with this handful of code, we can build the Holland Tunnel.
我看不出
I don't see it.
我看不出  它是门  还是隧道
I don't. I mean, is it a door, or is it a tunnel?
还是巴别塔
Or is it the Tower of Babel?
还是罗赛达石  还是体育场
Or is it a Rosetta Stone, or is it a stadium?
你连隐喻都决定不了
You can't even decide on a metaphor.
如果浏览器是最重要的点子
And if the big idea here is the browser,
而且它那么容易搭建  那就不是个好点子
and it's that easy to build, then it's not a big idea at all.
是定局
It's a foregone conclusion.
而且这我们怎么能赢
And how can we win at something when anyone--
任何人  包括施乐  苹果
anyone, including Xerox and Apple
和超文本盛事上那些真正的玩家
and all the actual players from your little Hypertext shindig,
都随时能进来  碾压我们
can step in at any moment and crush us?
它是有竞争力的
It will be competitive,
把着门的人可以收入场费
because whoever owns the door can charge admission.
但我真心相信  有了这间屋子里的人
But I sincerely believe that with the people in this room,
我们有机会建造最好的...
we have a chance to build the best--
而且你凭什么认为
And what makes you think
这屋子里的人都会听你的  乔
you have all the people in this room, Joe?
走吧  卡梅  我们走
Come on, Cam, let's go.
Come on, Cam. Let's go.
我们废话少说  汤姆
Let's cut the bullshit, Tom.
你不是对这个点子不满
Your problem isn't the idea.
是啊  乔
You're right, Joe.
知道我对什么不满吗
Do you know what my problem is?
我不希望卡梅伦最终像莱恩一样
I don't want to see Cameron end up like Ryan.
汤姆
Tom!
你再敢说一次他的名字
You say his name one more time--
莱恩  你记得他吗
Ryan. Do you remember him?
幸好  配偶没有投票权
Well, hey, lucky for us, wives don't get a vote.
你
You--
天啊
Oh, my God.
汤姆
Tom!
乔
Joe!
Joe?!
快去
Go!
我知道  你没死算走运了
I know. You're lucky you're not dead.
乔  如果我们还有一丝机会
Listen, Joe, if we have any chance in hell at this,
这种私人问题
it's this kind of personal bullshit
会让我们根本没机会开始
that's going to sink us before we even start.
我们
Us?
是啊  卡梅伦说得对
Yeah, Cameron was right.
根本没有所谓未来  是吧
There's no such thing as the future, hey?
只有现在
All there is is now.
或许我们没有太早
Maybe we're not early.
或许如果我们现在做  就能做第一个
Maybe if we do it now, we could be the first.
不管怎样  我不想再等了
Regardless, I am done waiting.
我不能放过这次机会
I can't let this one get away.
那就别
Then don't.
他没事
Hey, he's fine.
他手腕断了  但没事
He broke his wrist, but he's okay.
计算机分销商展览上发生了什么
What happened at COMDEX?
什么  没什么啊
What? Nothing.
没发生什么
Nothing happened.
我需要透口气
I need some air.
你没事吧
You okay?
怪乔是那么简单
So easy to make Joe the bad guy.
我是说
I mean...
把他视作坏人  他就承担责任了
making him the villain takes the blame away,
但所有跟他有关的事
but in everything that's happened with him,
每一次
every single time...
我也是有错的
I deserve some of the blame, too.
跟你也是一样的
And it's the same with you, you know?
我们不欢而散
Things fell apart.
你做了你做的
And you did what you did,
但我也有很大的错
but a lot of it was my fault.
这是个很棒的点子
This is a really cool idea.
是啊  我也觉得
Yeah, I think so, too!
听着  如果乔对你是个问题
And, look, if Joe is a problem for you,
那他不非得在这儿的
then he doesn't have to be here.
我们可以摆脱他
We can get rid of him.
都接上了吗
We all patched in?
嗯  试试吧
Yeah, give it a try.
进去了  速度很好
Yup, we're in, good and speedy.
这就是你的宝贝
So, this is your baby, huh?
嗯  厉害的小网络
Yeah, the little network that could.
NeXT的数字信号处理器挺厉害
The DSP in this cube is amazing.
不仅有56k速
Not only are we getting clean 56K,
还能同时干这个
we can do this at the same time.
听上去不错吧
Sounds pretty good, huh?
是光驱播放的吗
Yeah, is that coming off the CD-ROM?
我们该集中注意力了
We should really focus.
好了  从国家科学基金网能接到CERN上
Okay, so through NSFNET, we can connect to CERN?
对  但到了欧洲就得爬了
Yes, but we're gonna crawl once we jump to Europe.
为什么  TAT8通信电缆是光纤
Why? The TAT-8 is fiber optic.
但它埋在大陆架下面
Yeah, but it's also buried along the continental shelf
一直有鲨鱼袭击
and constantly being attacked by sharks.
据说是它们能感应到电辐射
Apparently, they can sense the electrical radiation.
是啊
I know.
我爱你的大脑
I love your mind.
七千一个还是太贵
You know, seven grand a pop is still insane,
而且不知道为什么要用镁做
and I don't know why the cube is magnesium,
但我还是喜欢好机器
but I still appreciate a good machine.
是啊
Yeah, well...
人说  软件来来去去
you know what they say, software comes and goes...
硬件恒久远
But hardware is forever.
好了  都带好了吧
Okay. Do you have everything?
嗯
Yeah.
好  这很好
Okay, this is good. This is good.
我今天把会都开完
Yeah, I'll knock out my meetings today
早点回去
and get in a few days early,
见见家人  适应一下
I'll see the family, get my bearings.
应该能帮我缓过来
I think-- I think it will help me recalibrate.
嗯  这样很好
Yeah, this is good.
嗯  我后天去
Yeah, and I'll pick you up at the airport
机场接你
day after tomorrow, okay?
-我会去的  -好
- I'll be there. - Okay.
等等
Wait, um...
很抱歉我没相信你
I'm really sorry that I didn't trust you.
我不喜欢我这周末的样子
I don't like who I've been this weekend.
我也觉得很奇怪
It's been a weird situation for me, too.
那天晚上在旅馆
The other night at the hotel,
我是在用你的电脑看你的电邮
I was reading your emails on your laptop.
我真不敢相信我那么做了
I can't believe that I did that.
我就是忍不住不去想乔
I just couldn't get Joe out of my head,
那非常不理智  我很抱歉
and it was completely irrational and I'm sorry.
我不希望我们对彼此撒谎
I just-- don't want us to lie to one another.
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
-好  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
乔
Joe...
乔  我...
Joe, I am...
乔  我想再次为昨天的事道歉
Joe, I-- I just wanted to apologize again for yesterday.
我的行为
The way I behaved...
我太过分了
I was way, way, way out of line.
我也过分了
I was out of line, too.
抱歉
Sorry.
-我爱你  -我爱你
- I love you. - Love you.
-回见  -嗯
- I'll see you. - Okay.
楼下准备好了
Hey, they're ready downstairs.
唐娜
Donna...
我不能跟你合作
I can't work with you.
什么
What?
我不能跟你合作
I can't work with you.
不可能回到从前了
It will never be like it was.
不可能了
It can't be.
但昨晚  我们还谈了
But last night, we-- we talked.
还好好的
It was good.
我不明白
I don't understand.
知道我为什么要在这里见面吗
You know why I wanted us to meet here?
我不想忘记发生的事
I just didn't want to forget what had happened,
以及那多么痛苦
how painful that was.
为什么
Why?
我昨晚差点忘了
And then I almost did forget last night
我们谈时  感觉很好
when we talked, when it felt good,
我的朋友又回来了
when I was with my friend again.
然后你提醒了我
And then you reminded me
你多轻易就抛弃别人
how easily you toss people aside
只要你觉得他们挡了你的路
when you feel like they're in your way.
你是为了乔
This about Joe.
不  是你
No, this is about you.
天呐
Jesus!
我是想帮你
I was trying to help you.
我一直都只想帮你
All I was ever trying to do was help you.
好吧
Well...
问题是  唐娜
the thing is, Donna,
我喜欢这个项目
I love this project...
我想好好开发它
and I want to work on it.
拿走吧
Take it.
该死
Damn it.
是我  我这就去办公室
It's me. I'm headed to the office.
我要飞去瑞士
I need a flight to Switzerland
等我到了要见CERN
and I need to meet with CERN when I get there.
卡梅伦呢
Where the hell is Cameron?
你知道这四年
You know how long I've been waiting,
我等了多久  闲坐着无所事事
just sitting around the last four years, twiddling my thumbs?
或许我们在未来上下的赌注终于能有结果了
Maybe this futures bet we made will finally pay off.
我爱她
I'm in love with her.
唐娜呢
Where's Donna?
她走了
She left.
好吧
All right.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.